Lee Goullaud | Front End Developer

Vancouver, BC | US citizen | 604-773-0145 | egoullaud@gmail.com | Portfolio | LinkedIn

DEVELOPER PROJECTS

Strolls: a Walking Adventure:

Nov 2022

Rails app built with React front end using TailwindCSS, Mapbox, and Figma for design. The app is currently being rebuilt in React Native. The app allows a user to look up their neighborhood and find points of interest to explore and add photos of their own.

Gamerverse: Nov 2022

Designed and built this personal project to search and view video games. Built using RAWG API, React, and TailwindCSS.

Grandma Finch's Maple Syrup:

Oct 2022

Designed and built a responsive website for a mom and pop maple syrup business. Made with React and TailwindCSS.

Raine Gauthier Photography:

Sept 2022

Designed and built a 10-page gallery website for a client with HTML5, CSS3, & JavaScript.

AWARDS

Girl Develop It Hack for Health Hackathon

Nov 2022

• Second Place Prize: Strolls: a Walking Adventure

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer

Remote

Upwork.ca

Jul 2022 - Present

- Designed and built fully responsive websites for clients using Figma, React, Next JS, JS and CSS (including TailwindCSS, Bootstrap 5).
- Designed and built websites using REST APIs and GraphQL, headless CMS.
- Designed and built websites using WordPress, Squarespace, Wix

Independent Contractor Flowers by Elizabeth

Greater Vancouver, BC Feb 2015 - Dec 2021

- Created contracting company specializing in garden design, maintenance, and winter tree pruning, servicing 150+ clients.
- Developed and managed 350+ projects, and 30+ long-term contracts, growing the client list by 40%.

ABOUT ME

I am a web developer with a background in conservation science and 6 years of experience in leadership, education, and collaborative roles. I have built numerous websites and applications for clients, using React, Next.js, Javascript, headless CMS, and RESTful APIs. I am searching for a full-time position in web development.

DEVELOPER SKILLS

React.js & Next.js
React Native
SQL
JavaScript ES6
HTML5 & CSS3
Bootstrap 5
API & REST API
TailwindCSS & Material UI
GraphQL & Graph CMS

TECH STACK

GitHub & Git
Figma
AdobeXD/Adobe Photoshop
Visual Studio Code
Kanban/Jira/Agile
Squarespace & Wordpress
Headless CMS

EDUCATION

Skillcrush Bootcamp, Front End Developer Course, August 2022

University of British Columbia, BSc. Natural Resource Conservation: Science & Management, 2018 • Built and maintained a Squarespace website, driving marketing and growing the customer base by 30%.

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent Mandarin - Intermediate

Team Leader Saje Natural Wellness

Tsawwassen, BC Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

- Managed conflicts and emotional needs of team of 8, increasing reported employee satisfaction to 95%.
- Facilitated leadership development in the team, resulting in the increased initiative, driving monthly sales to 130% of our goal.
- Supported management sales goals, resulting in leading Western Canada district sales for 13 months.

Environmental Restoration Team Leader Dillon Consulting Surrey, BC May 2018 - Dec 2018

- Managed 31+ environmentally-sensitive sites, reducing invasive species infestation by 80%.
- Attended 60+ educational events, increasing public awareness of our stewardship program.
- Hired, trained, and managed 20+ employees, increasing productivity by 75%.